modelav.com 2011-05-14

# Privacy Statement | Sport Aviator

**PRIVACY POLICY for the ACADEMY OF MODEL AERONAUTICS WEB SITE**  

Introduction  
Welcome to the Academy of Model Aeronautics Web site. This Privacy Policy is designed to tell you about our practices regarding the collection, use and disclosure of information that we collect from and about you. Please read this entire Privacy Policy carefully, so that youÆll understand our practices in these areas, and how they affect the use of the many offerings and programs on our Web site.

The AMA strives constantly to learn more about its members and visitors in order to better anticipate and fulfill their needs. In the course of these activities, the AMA gathers information about the members and visitors in a variety of ways to meet their great desire for customized information, services and promotions. In all of these activities, the AMA recognizes that members and visitors have a right to expect fair and reasonable practices regarding the collection, safeguarding, and use of any personal information we seek concerning them.

The Academy of Model Aeronautics does not knowingly collect personal information from children, except in cases of a new member completing an AMA membership application form on-line. In this situation, the AMA must have a signed consent form from a parent or legal guardian authorizing purchase of a new membership before it is processed.

**Guiding Principles**  
The AMA follows these general policies (explained in more detail below) with respect to all Web site visitors:

We provide members and visitors with reasonable opportunities to choose, or opt-out of, the collection of personally-identifiable information, and the sharing of that information with third parties.

We do not permit members to publicly pose or otherwise distribute personally-identifiable contact information.

Whenever we collect personally identifiable information, we take effective precautions to protect that data from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure or alteration.

We provide a mechanism through which members and visitors can contact the AMA with inquiries regarding our privacy practices.

This Web site is not directed to children under the age of 13. If you are under 13, please do not provide any personal information to the AMA without a parent or legal guardianÆs permission.

 ** _PARENTS:_** The AMA is concerned about the privacy of young children and does not knowingly collect any personal information from a child under 13. We strongly encourage you to take an active role in monitoring your childÆs access to the Internet and to our site to ensure that your childÆs privacy is well protected.

 **Personal Information Collected By The AMA And How The AMA Uses It**  
The Academy of Model Aeronautics collects personal information from our members and visitors only on a voluntary basis. We do not require this information for members and visitors to obtain access to our Web site. For instance, a user can explore the site without providing any personal information. In such cases, the only information we collect from the user will be the establishment of a _cookie_. No personal information is collected from users who limit their activities to participation in these activities.

The AMA may also permit users to send us an e-mail, but we do not maintain names, addresses, or the e-mails in our operational database on a continuing basis. We also do not share this information with third parties, other than third parties who provide support services to us, as described below.

**Non-Personal Information Collected By The AMA And How The AMA Uses It**  
The Academy of Model Aeronautics also collects aggregate, non-personal information on an ongoing basis when one views our Web site. The collection of this non-personal information is done through “ _cookie_ ” technology, as explained below. We also collect and analyze Internet Protocol Addresses, or “ _IP Addresses_ “.

**Cookies**  
Like many entities, we use “cookie” technology on and off of Web site. Cookies are pieces of information that a Web server transfers to an individualÆs hard drive for the purpose of keeping records. They enhance your online experience by saving your preferences while you are visiting a particular site. Our cookies do not contain any personally-identifiable information and cannot collect information from your hard drive.

When you view the AMAÆs Web site, we may place a “cookie” on your computer, which will be stored there permanently. Cookies are used for purposes such as counting the number of visits to our site and telling us whether you have visited us before or if you are a new visitor. The cookie doesnÆt obtain any personal information about you or provide us with any way to contact you, and the cookie does not extract any information from your computer. We do use the cookie technology to help us identify site features in which you have the greatest interest, so that we can provide more of what you may want. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Remember, though, that cookies allow you to take full advantage of all the AMA Web siteÆs features, and we recommend that you leave them turned on.

**IP Addresses**  
When you visit our site, we become aware of your Internet Protocol Address, also known as your “IP Address”. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. Your IP address also is used to gather broad demographic information about users of our Web site (e.g., how many visitors come from an IP address in a particular state).

**Data Sharing And Transfer**  
The AMA does not sell, transfer or disclose personally-identifiable information gathered at the AMAÆs Web site to third parties without a parentÆs prior consent. There are only two exceptions to this rule: (1) In cases where we believe in good faith that it is necessary to disclose such information to prevent a crime or an injury to ourselves or to third parties; and (2) The AMA discloses information to _third parties who provide support services to us_ , as described below.

There may be times when we share aggregate information about our visitors (e.g., the percentage of male and female visitors to our site) with advertisers, business partners, sponsors and other third parties in an effort to customize or enhance the content and advertising of our site to potential users. We may also collect aggregate data from Web log files (such as your Web browser, operating system, pages visited, etc.) to understand how users navigate the site and what features are most popular, and we may share this information with third parties as well.

**Third Parties Who Provide Support Services**  
In the course of operating the Academy of Model Aeronautics, we employ other companies and individuals to perform a variety of functions on our behalf. For example, we hire agencies to help administer online member promotions, to analyze data, and to provide member service. These third parties and their employees may have access to personal information if it is needed to perform their functions; however, they are prohibited from using the personal information for other purposes, and they are required to maintain the information in confidence.

**Links To Other Web Sites**  
The Academy of Model Aeronautics Web site may contain links to other sites. The AMA makes every effort to link only to Web sites that share the AMAÆs commitment to the Guiding Principles stated above. Although we try our best to ensure that these links are safe for children, the privacy and data collection practices on any linked Web sites are entirely separate from the Academy of Model Aeronautics and are not covered by this Privacy Policy. Other Web sites, which may contain material not suitable for children, may also link to the Academy of Model Aeronautics Web site without our knowledge or consent. The AMA has no responsibility for the content, policies or actions of these Web sites.

**Accessing And Changing Personal Information**  
Any user can review any personal information we have collected from them, if we are still maintaining the information in our operational database. They may also have the information deleted from the database, and refuse to permit further collection or use of their information. If you are a user and wish to exercise these rights, please contact _the Membership Department_ as described below.

**Changes And Updates To The Privacy Policy**  
The AMA Web siteÆs content and features may be updated, revised, modified and supplemented. The AMA reserves the right to change the information, features, products, policies, promotions, disclosures and disclaimers that are in use at any time. Changes to this Privacy Policy will be posted on our Web site, so please check the Policy periodically. The continued use of the AMA Web site following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy will mean you accept these changes. This Privacy Policy was last updated on Dec. 12, 2001.

**How To Contact Us  
** If you have any questions, comments or concerns about our Privacy Policy, or the practices of this site, please contact the AMA as follows:

The Academy of Model Aeronautics  
5161 East Memorial Blvd.  
Muncie, IN 47302  
Attn: Membership Department – Privacy Policy Issues  
Ph. (765) 287-1256 (8:00 a.m. – 5:00 p.m. E.S.T. Monday – Friday)  
or E-mail us at __[modelaircraft.org](mailto:webmaster@modelaircraft.org)__.

The Academy of Model Aeronautics will be happy to answer your questions, hear your concerns, or provide access to information in accordance with this Policy.
